<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Bitstamp blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/feed.xml</link>
        <description>Bitstamp Blog RSS feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 11:30:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>Bitstamp</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forbes gives Bitstamp a perfect 10/10 in transparency & audit strength]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/forbes-gives-bitstamp-a-perfect-1010-in-transparency-and-audit-strength/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/forbes-gives-bitstamp-a-perfect-1010-in-transparency-and-audit-strength/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bitstamp has been recognized as one of “The world’s most trustworthy crypto exchanges” in Forbes’ annual Best Crypto Exchange rankings!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Transparency, regulation, and security have been the foundation of Bitstamp since 2011, making us the longest-running crypto exchange in the industry. These pillars define how we operate every day, and now, <strong>Forbes has validated our approach.</strong></p><p>In their <strong>2025 Crypto Exchange rankings</strong>, Bitstamp earned a <strong>perfect 10/10 in both transparency and audit strength. </strong>A testament to the standards we uphold. We also received the second-highest score in regulation among all exchanges.</p><p>And the recognition doesn’t stop there. Forbes ranked us in the<strong> top 3 most trustworthy crypto exchanges globally— and the most trusted among Europe-based exchanges!</strong></p><p><em>“The firm exemplifies many of the criteria valued in the ranking methodology: large asset base, ownership clarity, a credible audit history, and a robust crypto product offering.”</em> – Forbes</p><p>When independent industry leaders validate our work, it reaffirms the effort we put in every day to run things the right way.</p><p>For all the details, you can <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/javierpaz/2025/01/28/the-worlds-most-trustworthy-crypto-exchanges/" rel="noreferrer noopener">read the full Forbes article.</a></p><h2 id="our-three-operational-pillars">Our three operational pillars</h2><h3 id="transparency-10-10-in-transparency-audit-strength">Transparency – 10/10 in transparency &amp; audit strength</h3><p>Our perfect 10/10 Forbes score in transparency and audit strength reflects the rigorous financial controls we have in place. Since 2016, we have been audited annually by a Big Four global accounting firm, ensuring that every process is independently verified. Besides external audits, our internal review mechanisms continuously strengthen our control environment, setting the highest standards for accountability in crypto.</p><h3 id="regulation-among-the-highest-rated-exchanges">Regulation – among the highest-rated exchanges</h3><p>Regulation is a daily commitment to operating by the book. We hold 50+ licenses and registrations across key global markets, demonstrating our dedication to compliance. Nearly 30% of our workforce is dedicated to compliance, legal, risk management, and similar ensuring that every decision we make aligns with the highest industry standards.</p><h3 id="security-industry-leading-protection-since-2011">Security – industry-leading protection since 2011</h3><p>Trust starts with security, and at Bitstamp, safeguarding customer assets has been our top priority since day one. 100% of customer funds are backed and available for withdrawal at any time, stored separately from corporate assets for maximum protection. With an industry-leading 99.9% uptime, our infrastructure is built for reliability.</p><h2 id="a-reputation-built-on-trust">A reputation built on trust</h2><p>And it’s not just us saying it. Independent industry leaders continue to recognize our efforts, with Forbes and CCData ranking us among the best.</p><ul><li><strong>Forbes Exchange Rankings </strong>– In 2024 we were recognized as one of the top two regulated crypto spot exchanges operating globally. This year, we’re back on the <em>"World’s most trustworthy crypto exchanges"</em> podium, earning a perfect 10/10 in two categories.</li><li><strong>CCData</strong> – Achieved seven consecutive AA ratings, the highest possible score, reinforcing our dedication to security and transparency.</li></ul><p>If you’re looking for a crypto exchange you can trust, one with an over-a-decade-long track record of transparency, compliance, and security, welcome.</p><p>Create a <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitstamp account today.</a></p><hr><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about risks here.</em></p><p><em>Bitstamp is licensed to engage in virtual currency business activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitstamp Monthly Briefing – December 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-monthly-briefing-december-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-monthly-briefing-december-2024/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Key market movements, top assets, and what’s next for crypto. Get all the highlights from December 2024 and a look ahead to 2025.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>December brought a slowdown after November’s big rally, with the total market cap dipping slightly. But trading stayed strong, and standout assets like Bitget Token and Hedera saw impressive gains.</p><p>With 2025 kicking off, the market is gearing up for changes. Regulatory shifts, new blockchain tech, and rising institutional interest.</p><p>Here’s your quick rundown of December’s market trends, top and worst performers, and a look ahead to the coming year. Let’s get started!</p><h2 id="market-update">Market update</h2><p>The total crypto market cap declined by 4.5% month-over-month, reaching $3.18 trillion at the end of December. Trading volume on the leading crypto spot exchanges we monitor increased by 5% during this period.</p><p>Bitcoin's market dominance rose by 0.85 percentage points month-over-month to 58.1%.</p><p><strong>Total crypto market cap </strong>(grey)<strong> and BTC dominance </strong>(green)</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://blog.bitstamp.net/bts-img/2025/01/btc-dominance-dec.png" class="kg-image" alt="bitcoin dominance december"><figcaption><em>Source: </em><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/TOTAL/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em><strong>Total crypto market cap</strong></em></a><em><strong>,</strong></em><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTC.D/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em><strong>Bitcoin dominance</strong></em></a></figcaption></figure><p><em>Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of crypto assets can be highly volatile. Data taken on January 1, 2025. </em></p><h3 id="best-performing-cmc-100-assets-in-december">Best performing CMC 100 assets in December</h3><ul><li><strong>+271.4% Bitget Token (BGB) – </strong>The<strong> </strong>price surge was <a href="https://www.bitget.com/news/detail/12560604431022" rel="noreferrer noopener">driven by</a> regulatory approval in El Salvador, expansion into European markets, new partnerships and product offerings, and record-breaking trading volumes.</li><li><strong>+120.6% Virtuals Protocol (VIRTUAL) – </strong>Maintained a strong uptrend, fueled by <a href="https://cryptoticker.io/en/virtuals-protocol-price-momentum-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener">increased interest</a> in AI Agent Applications.</li><li><strong>+58.1% Hedera (HBAR) – </strong>Sustained <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/hedera/" rel="noreferrer noopener">strong momentum</a> following the US election.</li></ul><h3 id="worst-performing-cmc-100-assets-in-december">Worst performing CMC 100 assets in December</h3><ul><li><strong>-46.4% Core (CORE) – </strong><a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/core-dao/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Retraced sharply</a> at the beginning of the month after encountering strong resistance at the $2 level.</li><li><strong>-44.8% Celestia (TIA) – </strong>Lost momentum <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/celestia/" rel="noreferrer noopener">after a strong uptrend in November</a>, erasing all the gains from the previous month.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>-42.4% Worldcoin (WLD) – </strong>struggled to maintain its earlier performance and experienced a steady decline after <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/worldcoin-org/" rel="noreferrer noopener">failing to break the $4 resistance</a> level.</li></ul><p><em>Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of crypto assets can be highly volatile. Data taken on January 1, 2025. </em></p><h3 id="key-macro-crypto-events-in-january-2025">Key macro &amp; crypto events in January 2025</h3><ul><li><strong>January 8</strong>: US FOMC Minutes</li><li><strong>January 14</strong>: US PPI MoM</li><li><strong>January 14-15</strong>: <a href="https://lu.ma/cfc-st-moritz-public-days" rel="noreferrer noopener">CfC St. Moritz 2025 Public Days</a> in St. Moritz, Switzerland</li><li><strong>January 15</strong>: US Inflation &amp; Core Inflation rate</li><li><strong>January 17-19</strong>: <a href="https://bitcoinmedellin.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin Medellin Conference 2025</a> in Medellin, Colombia</li><li><strong>January 18</strong>: <a href="https://bitcoinday.io/naples25" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin Day Naples</a> in Naples, Florida, US</li><li><strong>January 20-24</strong>: <a href="https://web3hubdavos.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web3Hub Davos 2025</a> in Davos, Switzerland</li><li><strong>January 22-24</strong>: <a href="https://wagmi.miami/" rel="noreferrer noopener">WGMI 2025</a> in Miami, Florida, US</li><li><strong>January 22</strong>: <a href="https://davosweb3.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Davos Web3 Roundtable</a> in Davos, Switzerland</li><li><strong>January 25-26</strong>: <a href="https://www.thecounterparty.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Counterparty</a> in Miami, Florida, US</li><li><strong>January 29</strong>: US FED Interest Rate decision and press conference</li><li><strong>January 30-31</strong>: <a href="https://ethereumzuri.ch/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum Zürich</a> in Zürich, Switzerland</li><li><strong>January 30-31</strong>: <a href="https://planb.sv/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Plan ₿ Forum El Salvador</a> in San Salvador, El Salvador</li><li><strong>January 30</strong>: Governing Council of the ECB in Frankfurt, Germany</li></ul><h2 id="2025-crypto-market-outlook-a-comprehensive-overview">2025 crypto market outlook: a comprehensive overview</h2><p>The year 2025 promises to be pivotal for the cryptocurrency market, with a blend of bullish sentiment, emerging trends, and evolving technological and regulatory landscapes shaping the industry's trajectory. For a comprehensive outlook, we’ve gathered insights from Bitcoin Magazine, a16z, and Bernstein analysts, which highlight a data-driven, optimistic future driven by innovation, institutional adoption, and increasing mainstream integration.</p><h3 id="bitcoin-a-bullish-momentum">Bitcoin: a bullish momentum</h3><p>Bitcoin Magazine emphasizes a data-driven approach to 2025, using metrics like the MVRV Z-Score and Pi Cycle Oscillator. These indicators suggest significant upside potential for Bitcoin, drawing parallels to its exponential growth phases in previous cycles. Analysts project a possible price range of $140,000 to $210,000, driven by macroeconomic factors such as a weakening U.S. Dollar Index and an expanding global money supply. Bernstein forecasts align with these trends, predicting Bitcoin to reach $200,000 by year-end, bolstered by corporate treasury demand and institutional inflows into Bitcoin ETFs.</p><p>Bernstein notes that Bitcoin’s corporate adoption, led by firms like MicroStrategy, could double treasury investments to over $50 billion. Simultaneously, ETFs are expected to capture $70 billion in institutional inflows, further solidifying Bitcoin’s role as a long-term asset. This “sticky” demand represents a shift from speculative trading to strategic holdings, potentially reducing market volatility.</p><h3 id="emerging-trends-and-innovations">Emerging trends and innovations</h3><p>Both a16z and Bernstein predict a surge in stablecoin adoption, driven by cost-effective cross-border payments and enterprise applications. Stablecoins, already pivotal in the peer-to-peer payment space, are expected to gain broader acceptance among small and medium enterprises (SMEs) and large corporations, potentially reaching $500 billion in market size.</p><p>The rise of decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs) is gaining momentum with the introduction of legal frameworks like Wyoming’s DUNA, empowering decentralized governance. This trend reflects broader adoption of public blockchains for applications such as digital government bonds, enhancing transparency and efficiency in financial markets.</p><p>Bitcoin miners are diversifying into AI-driven data center operations; a shift highlighted by Bernstein. This integration of AI with crypto infrastructure may attract institutional interest and improve mining stability.</p><h3 id="regulatory-and-institutional-developments">Regulatory and institutional developments</h3><p>Regulatory clarity is expected to improve in 2025, particularly in the U.S., where the SEC and CFTC are anticipated to establish clearer frameworks for digital assets. This environment could spur a wave of crypto-related IPOs and encourage traditional financial institutions to expand their crypto offerings, including custody services and DeFi-focused funds.</p><p>Ethereum is projected to solidify its status as the second most valuable blockchain, driven by its deflationary supply dynamics and utility in decentralized finance (DeFi). As adoption grows, Ethereum is expected to attract additional institutional investment, enhancing both its price performance and broader ecosystem.</p><h3 id="mainstream-integration-and-user-experience">Mainstream integration and user experience</h3><p>A16z emphasizes the importance of simplifying blockchain technologies to drive adoption. As user interfaces become more user-friendly, the industry could see passive crypto holders transition into active participants, expanding the user base for applications across DeFi, NFTs, gaming, and social platforms.</p><p>The emergence of dedicated app stores and decentralized marketplaces is eliminating barriers posed by centralized platforms. These innovations aim to provide seamless access to crypto services, fostering widespread adoption of decentralized applications.</p><h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3><p>The 2025 crypto market outlook presents a combination of optimism and transformation. Bitcoin’s growth potential, stablecoin adoption, and regulatory clarity are complemented by technological advancements in blockchain and AI integration. While challenges remain, the convergence of institutional interest, improved infrastructure, and mainstream integration positions the crypto industry for a landmark year in its evolution toward financial and technological maturity.</p><h2 id="recommended-reads">Recommended reads</h2><h3 id="are-we-bullish-enough">Are We Bullish Enough?</h3><p><strong>By </strong><a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/are-we-bullish-enough-redux/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong></a></p><p>In 2020, the author predicted that the S&amp;P 500 could quadruple in nominal value by 2030 based on historical patterns of 10-year returns following similar prior 20-year performance. This projection, which initially seemed bold, now appears less far-fetched, given the index’s progress halfway to the target; especially when accounting for inflation. Adjusted for inflation, historical periods with comparable returns suggest more modest growth of 1.75x to 2.75x in real terms. While this predictive model has limitations and relies on overlapping data, it demonstrates a surprisingly strong historical relationship between past and future stock returns. Heading into 2025, the author maintains a medium-to-long-term bullish outlook on U.S. stocks, despite current valuation concerns.</p><h3 id="blockchain-unicorns">Blockchain Unicorns </h3><p><strong>By </strong><a href="https://www.blockchaincoinvestors.com/blog/blockchain-is-responsible-for-nearly-1-in-5-global-unicorns-today" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Blockchain Coinvestors</strong></a></p><p>Blockchain technology now accounts for nearly 20% of global unicorns, with 237 blockchain ventures and crypto projects valued at over $1 billion by the end of 2024. This rapid growth, reaching a combined valuation of over $3 trillion in just 15 years since Bitcoin's inception, mirrors the development of Web1 and Web2 but at a faster pace. Public blockchain companies like Coinbase have experienced significant valuation increases, and analysts predict continued dominance in the financial space. Despite this progress, adoption remains in its early stages, with 93% of the global population and most major institutions yet to invest. As blockchain continues to revolutionize digital finance, the potential for historical returns remains immense for early investors.</p><h3 id="the-where-are-we-in-this-bitcoin-cycle-on-chain-update">The Where Are We in This Bitcoin Cycle: On-Chain Update</h3><p><strong>By </strong><a href="https://bmpro.substack.com/p/where-are-we-in-this-bitcoin-cycle" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>The Bitcoin Magazine</strong></a></p><p>Bitcoin's recent surge past $100,000, with projections of reaching $200,000, underscores the importance of analyzing key on-chain metrics to anticipate market trends. Indicators such as Terminal Price, Puell Multiple, MVRV Z-Score, and Value Days Destroyed (VDD) highlight the current phase of the bull market, suggesting substantial upside potential remains. Metrics like SOPR and Active Address Sentiment, while pointing to profit-taking and temporary overbought conditions, still indicate healthy market dynamics with room for further growth. Historical patterns suggest a peak may still be months away, with resistance levels likely emerging between $150,000 and $200,000.</p><h3 id="the-traps-of-passive-investing">The Traps of Passive Investing</h3><p><strong>By </strong><a href="https://www.institutionalinvestor.com/article/2e5um1swovwbm3x5yyk1s/corner-office/why-michael-green-is-known-as-the-cassandra-of-passive-investing" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Michael Green</strong></a></p><p>Michael Green, a prominent asset manager and former hedge fund manager, has spent years warning about the risks of passive investing, arguing that it distorts markets, concentrates capital, and could lead to instability. With passive strategies now accounting for nearly half of market control, Green claims they reinforce momentum, reduce price discovery, and undermine capital allocation to smaller companies. He warns of a potential market crash if passive inflows slow due to demographic shifts or economic downturns, as passive investors lack cash reserves to stabilize markets. While critics downplay his thesis as theoretical or self-serving, Green’s analysis resonates with some hedge fund managers and short-sellers grappling with a market increasingly dominated by algorithmic and index-driven trading.</p><hr><p><em>No information in this blog is intended to provide any personal investment services or advice nor is it an investment recommendation. Clients are responsible for making their own investment decisions. Bitstamp accepts no responsibility for any damage and/or loss arising from the use of information provided herein. Past performance is not necessarily an indicator of future results. Please consider your individual position and financial goals before making an independent investment decision. </em></p><p><em>Bitstamp is licensed to engage in virtual currency business activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</em></p><p><em>Not offered in the following states: Hawaii and Nevada</em></p><p><em>This blog post has been approved as a financial promotion by Bitstamp UK Limited which is registered with the UK’s Financial Conduct Authority. Please read the </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Risk Warning Statement</em></a><em> before investing. Cryptoassets and cryptoasset services are not regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. You are unlikely to be protected if something goes wrong. Your investment may go down as well as up. You may be liable to pay Capital Gains Tax on any profits you earn.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New listing: $MELANIA and $TRUMP meme coins on Bitstamp]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/new-listing-melania-and-trump-meme-coins-on-bitstamp/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/new-listing-melania-and-trump-meme-coins-on-bitstamp/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bitstamp is now listing Official Melania Meme ($MELANIA) and OFFICIAL TRUMP ($TRUMP). You can start trading these new meme coins today.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’re expanding our lineup of assets with two new meme coins: OFFICIAL TRUMP ($TRUMP) and Official Melania Meme ($MELANIA). Both are now available for trading on Bitstamp!</p><h2 id="listing-schedule">Listing schedule</h2><p>We’ve listed the following pairs globally.*</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/trump/usd/">TRUMP/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/trump/eur/">TRUMP/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/melania/usd/">MELANIA/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/melania/eur/">MELANIA/EUR</a></p><p>Let’s now take a closer look at each of the assets.</p><h2 id="more-about-official-trump-trump-">More about OFFICIAL TRUMP ($TRUMP)</h2><p>The TRUMP token is a meme cryptocurrency associated with Donald Trump, the 45th and current 47th President of the United States, and his ideals and beliefs. It is issued on the Solana blockchain as an SPL token and has a total supply of 1 billion tokens, with 200 million currently in circulation as of January 2025.</p><p>For more information, read our detailed article <em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-trump-meme-trump/">What is $TRUMP?</a></em></p><h2 id="more-about-official-melania-meme-melania-">More about Official Melania Meme ($MELANIA)</h2><p>Official Melania Meme is a meme coin and digital collectible designed to reflect support for the values associated with Melania Trump, the current First Lady of the United States. This token combines meme culture with digital assets. With a total supply of 1 billion tokens, MELANIA quickly gained attention, reaching a $2 billion market cap shortly after its launch.</p><p>Learn all about it by reading our detailed article <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-melania-meme-melania/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>What is $MELANIA?</em></a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/onboarding/login/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log in</a> to your Bitstamp account to start trading and get the Bitstamp mobile app (available on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitstamp-buy-btc-and-more/id1406825640" rel="noreferrer noopener">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.bitstamp.app&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>) to trade all our cryptocurrencies on the go!</p><hr><p><em>*The listing schedule times might be subject to change. The pairs are listed globally, except in the US.</em></p><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="nofollow"><em>risks</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitstamp Earn Lending: December 2024 Performance Report is here]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-earn-lending-december-2024-performance-report-is-here/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-earn-lending-december-2024-performance-report-is-here/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Get a clear view of Bitstamp Earn Lending’s performance in December 2024 with key insights and straightforward analysis.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>December wrapped up a steady and consistent year for Bitstamp Earn Lending. With the markets settling after a dynamic year, our focus remained on delivering reliable performance and transparent updates to keep you informed.</p><p>Our <strong>December 2024 Lending Performance Report</strong> is now live. This report is designed to give you a clear and simple view of how our lending product performed last month.</p><h2 id="what-s-inside-the-report"><strong>What’s inside the report?</strong></h2><p>Here’s what you can expect:</p><ul><li><strong>Portfolio activity:</strong> A detailed look at performance metrics, loan activity, and asset distribution.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Borrower metrics:</strong> Insights into borrower leverage and financial stability.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Risk management:</strong> How collateral levels were maintained, and risks were managed.</li></ul><p>Our commitment to transparency means you’ll always get a clear picture of how our lending product is performing, with no unnecessary complexity.</p><p><a href="https://assets.bitstamp.net/msc/Lending_report_A4_dec_bfdf93a650.pdf ">Download the report</a>.</p><hr><p><em>* The availability of Bitstamp Earn Lending depends on many considerations, including the entity to which you are onboarded and the jurisdiction where you reside. Lending is not available in the US, UK, and Singapore.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitstamp welcomes CXT, BOME, POPCAT, and SYRUP!]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-welcomes-cxt-bome-popcat-and-syrup/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-welcomes-cxt-bome-popcat-and-syrup/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Discover the new assets on Bitstamp! Learn about CXT, BOME, POPCAT, and SYRUP, their unique features, and how they fit into your crypto world.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your portfolio just got more options. We’ve added four unique assets to Bitstamp, giving you new ways to explore blockchain innovation. From governance and DeFi yields to popular meme culture, there’s something for everyone in this latest lineup.</p><h2 id="listing-schedule"><strong>Listing schedule</strong></h2><p>We are listing the following pairs globally.*</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/cxt/usd/">CXT/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/cxt/eur/">CXT/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/bome/usd/">BOME/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/bome/eur/">BOME/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/popcat/usb/">POPCAT/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/popcat/eur/">POPCAT/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/syrup/usd/">SYRUP/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/syrup/eur/">SYRUP/EUR</a></p><h2 id="cxt-transparency-and-governance">CXT: Transparency and governance</h2><p>CXT powers the Covalent Network, a platform that makes Ethereum’s blockchain data transparent and accessible for developers, researchers, and anyone who needs it. CXT also gives holders a voice in network governance, allowing them to vote on updates and decisions that shape the future of the platform. All in all, CXT offers a unique combination of utility and transparency.</p><h2 id="bome-memes-on-the-blockchain">BOME: Memes on the blockchain</h2><p>BOME, short for Book of Meme, is a Solana-based meme coin created to preserve internet culture. It’s a digital archive that immortalizes memes using decentralized storage solutions like IPFS and Arweave. Basically, it’s a digital museum for memes, keeping them alive and forever stored on the blockchain. Created by Darkfarms, BOME is where creativity, humor, and blockchain collide.</p><h2 id="popcat-an-asset-with-personality">POPCAT: An asset with personality</h2><p>POPCAT celebrates the viral Popcat meme, famous for its playful depiction of a cat’s popping mouth. This Solana-based token thrives on community engagement, channeling the meme’s popularity into a blockchain-driven project. Whether you’re a fan of the viral Popcat game or just love lighthearted tokens, POPCAT is here to add some playfulness to your portfolio.</p><h2 id="syrup-defi-yields-simplified">SYRUP: DeFi yields simplified</h2><p>SYRUP connects you to consistent DeFi yields through Maple’s institutional lending platform. Backed by overcollateralized loans to trusted borrowers, SYRUP offers returns on stablecoins like USDC and USDT. What sets it apart? The ability to earn reliable yields while also accessing liquidity through integration with other DeFi protocols. For anyone looking to maximize returns while keeping things simple, SYRUP brings a proven track record of sustainable yield generation.</p><p><strong>Ready to trade? </strong></p><p>Each of these assets brings something unique to the table, whether it’s governance, memes, or DeFi innovation. Explore their features, see if they fit into your portfolio, and start trading them on Bitstamp today.</p><p>Check them out today!</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/onboarding/login/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log in</a> to your Bitstamp account to start trading and get the Bitstamp app (available on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitstamp-buy-btc-and-more/id1406825640" rel="noreferrer noopener">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.bitstamp.app&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>) to trade all our cryptocurrencies on the go!</p><hr><p><em>*The pairs are listed globally, except in Singapore and the United States.  </em></p><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>risks</em></a><em>.  </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US holiday notice: Incoming and outgoing USD payments paused on January 20, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/us-holiday-notice-incoming-and-outgoing-usd-payments-paused-on-january-20-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/us-holiday-notice-incoming-and-outgoing-usd-payments-paused-on-january-20-2025/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bitstamp incoming and outgoing USD payments will be paused on Monday, January 20, 2025, due to a public holiday in the US.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Due to the upcoming public holiday (Martin Luther King Jr. Day) in the US on Monday, January 20, 2025, Bitstamp bank payment clearing system for incoming and outgoing USD payments won’t be available.</p><p>EUR SEPA transfers, GBP FPS transfers, credit card, Google Pay, Apple Pay, and PayPal transfers will remain unaffected.</p><p>If you need any help or additional information, please contact us at <a href="https://about:blank/" rel="noreferrer noopener">support@bitstamp.net</a><a href="https://about:blank/" rel="noreferrer noopener">.</a></p><p>We wish a peaceful Martin Luther King Jr. Day to our US customers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USA, you can now trade GYEN, ZUSD, BONK, and SUI on Bitstamp]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/usa-you-can-now-trade-gyen-zusd-bonk-and-sui-on-bitstamp/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/usa-you-can-now-trade-gyen-zusd-bonk-and-sui-on-bitstamp/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bitstamp adds GYEN, ZUSD, BONK, and SUI to its lineup in the USA. Learn what these new assets offer and why they’re worth exploring.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can now trade <strong>GYEN</strong>, <strong>ZUSD</strong>, <strong>BONK</strong>, and <strong>SUI</strong> on Bitstamp in the USA, including in New York State.</p><p>If you’re looking for new stablecoin options, we’ve got GYEN and ZUSD – both backed 1:1 by fiat currencies. If community favorites are your thing, BONK is a popular pick in the meme coin world. And if you’re all about innovation, SUI is helping build the next generation of decentralized apps.</p><h2 id="start-trading-new-assets-in-the-us-today">Start trading new assets in the US today</h2><p>We’re listing the following trading pairs:</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/gyen/usd/">GYEN/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/zusd/usd/">ZUSD/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/bonk/usd/">BONK/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/sui/usd/">SUI/USD</a></p><h2 id="more-about-gyen">More about GYEN</h2><p>GYEN is the world’s first regulated Japanese Yen stablecoin, issued by the reputable GMO-Z.com Trust Company and regulated by the New York Department of Financial Services (NYDFS). Each GYEN is backed 1:1 by the Japanese Yen. For anyone looking to diversify their portfolio with a globally recognized currency, GYEN is a solid choice.</p><p>Learn more in our article <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-gyen/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>What is GYEN?</em></a></p><h2 id="more-about-zusd">More about ZUSD</h2><p>Just like GYEN, <strong>ZUSD</strong> is also issued by <strong>GMO-Z.com Trust Company</strong>, but it’s pegged to the US Dollar. This gives you the reliability of the USD, with the flexibility and speed of cryptocurrency. With strong regulatory backing, ZUSD might be an interesting option for you.</p><p>Learn more in our article <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-zusd/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>What is ZUSD?</em></a></p><h2 id="more-about-sui">More about SUI</h2><p><strong>SUI</strong> is a next gen blockchain designed to support the future of decentralized apps (dApps). As the world’s first permissionless Layer 1 blockchain, SUI stands out with its ability to process simple transactions in parallel, making it faster and more scalable than many other blockchains. The native token, <strong>SUI</strong>, is used to power the network. It helps pay for transaction fees, rewards validators for securing the network, and keeps everything running smoothly.</p><p>Learn more in our article <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/en-gb/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-sui/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>What is SUI?</em></a></p><h2 id="more-about-bonk">More about BONK</h2><p>BONK is a meme coin that has gained popularity within the Solana community, known for its dog-themed branding and active social engagement. Created as an alternative to traditional financial systems, BONK encourages community involvement, allowing users to take part in governance and decision-making. It’s a platform that emphasizes accessibility and participation in the crypto space.</p><p>Learn more in our article <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-bonk/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>What is BONK?</em></a></p><h2 id="ready-to-explore-these-new-assets">Ready to explore these new assets? </h2><p>We’re dedicated to bringing diverse options to our US customers, and these listings do just that.</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/onboarding/login/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log in</a> to your Bitstamp account to start trading and get the Bitstamp mobile app (available on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitstamp-buy-btc-and-more/id1406825640" rel="noreferrer noopener">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.bitstamp.app&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>) to trade all our cryptocurrencies on the go!</p><hr><p>Bitstamp USA, Inc. is licensed to engage in Virtual Currency Business Activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</p><p>Don't invest unless you're prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and you should not expect to be protected if something goes wrong.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Ripple USD (RLUSD). Your next enterprise-grade stablecoin on Bitstamp.]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/introducing-ripple-usd-rlusd-your-next-enterprise-grade-stablecoin-on-bitstamp/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/introducing-ripple-usd-rlusd-your-next-enterprise-grade-stablecoin-on-bitstamp/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Ripple USD (RLUSD) on ETH network now on Bitstamp. Learn how it unlocks liquidity, enterprise solutions, and cross-border transactions.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’ve added Ripple USD (RLUSD) on Ethereum network to our diverse range of assets. Built with Ripple’s 10+ years of enterprise expertise, RLUSD is a robust solution designed for institutional-grade financial use cases, including payments and tokenization.</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/dashboard/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Start exploring</a></p><h2 id="listing-schedule">Listing schedule</h2><p>We are listing the following pairs globally.*</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/rlusd/eur/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / Euro EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/rlusd/usd/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / USD Dollar</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/rlusd/usdt/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / USDT</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/btc/rlusd/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / Bitcoin BTC</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/eth/rlusd/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / Ethereum ETH</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/xrp/rlusd/" rel="noreferrer noopener">RLUSD / XRP</a></p><h2 id="what-is-ripple-usd-rlusd-">What is Ripple USD (RLUSD)?</h2><p><strong>Ripple USD (RLUSD)</strong> is a stablecoin designed to maintain a steady value of one US dollar. While RLUSD is supported on both the XRP Ledger and Ethereum blockchains, we’re currently listing it on the Ethereum network. RLUSD is fully backed by cash and cash equivalents. This backing is intended to allow each RLUSD to be redeemable 1:1 in US dollars.</p><h2 id="why-choose-rlusd">Why choose RLUSD?</h2><p>Trust and compliance are top priorities for Ripple, and RLUSD reflects these values. Here are the key points that make this stablecoin stand out.</p><ul><li><strong>Stability:</strong> Backed 1:1 to the US dollar, RLUSD offers consistent value for payments, tokenization, and more.</li><li><strong>Enterprise-grade trust: </strong>RLUSD is issued under a New York Trust Charter, providing top-tier trust and compliance.</li><li><strong>A key entry to DeFi:</strong> RLUSD enables developers and users to tap into decentralized finance on the XRP Ledger, unlocking countless opportunities.</li><li><strong>Global reach: </strong>Through partnerships, RLUSD provides easy on/off ramps between fiat, crypto, and stablecoins.</li></ul><p>To learn more about RLUSD and how it works, check out our detailed article, <strong><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-ripple-usd-rlusd/">What is RLUSD?</a></strong></p><h2 id="how-to-get-started-with-ripple-usd">How to get started with Ripple USD</h2><p>RLUSD on ETH network is now live on Bitstamp, and you can start exploring its potential today. Whether you’re looking to streamline your cross-border transactions or simply want a stable asset in your portfolio, RLUSD offers a range of possibilities.</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/onboarding/login/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log in</a> to your Bitstamp account to start trading and get the Bitstamp mobile app (available on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitstamp-buy-btc-and-more/id1406825640" rel="noreferrer noopener">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.bitstamp.app&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>) to trade all our cryptocurrencies on the go!</p><hr><p><em>*The listing schedule times might be subject to change. Not all pairs are available in all jurisdictions. The pairs are listed globally except the EU.</em></p><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>risks</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><em>Bitstamp USA, Inc. is licensed to engage in Virtual Currency Business Activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garanti BBVA Kripto partners with Bitstamp on providing crypto trading services for its clients]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/garanti-bbva-kripto-partners-with-bitstamp-on-providing-crypto-trading-services-for-its-clients/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/garanti-bbva-kripto-partners-with-bitstamp-on-providing-crypto-trading-services-for-its-clients/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Garanti BBVA Kripto partners with Bitstamp to provide secure crypto trading, boosting adoption and accessibility in Turkey's digital asset market.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, Garanti BBVA Kripto has announced its partnership with the world’s longest running crypto exchange Bitstamp to allow the bank’s customers to trade crypto.</p><p>This is the first liquidity provider partnership established between Garanti BBVA Kripto, a subsidiary of Garanti BBVA and a pioneer in its sector, and a crypto exchange. The cooperation shows how both organisations are constantly improving the services offered to clients.</p><p>A sector leader in both security and compliance, with more than 50 licences and registrations secured with financial regulators across the globe, Bitstamp will empower Garanti BBVA Kripto to provide cryptocurrency services. Bitstamp will serve this role as the primary liquidity provider for Garanti BBVA Kripto's customers across multiple currencies via Bitstamp-as-a-Service</p><p>The partnership therefore enables investors in the crypto asset ecosystem as well as traditional financial market participants to trade on an approved selection of digital assets, contributing to crypto accessibility and adoption in Turkey.</p><p>Speaking about the cooperation,<strong> Korcan Abalı, CEO of Garanti BBVA Kripto,</strong> said:</p><blockquote>“As Garanti BBVA Kripto, we have started to offer crypto services to our customers since 2023. While the environment is being shaped by legal regulations for digital assets in Turkey, as one of the market leaders, we aim to provide the best digital asset services and at the same time lead the healthy growth of the digital asset sector in accordance with the regulations.</blockquote><blockquote>“With this aim, while collaborating with valuable institutions, we evaluate the values of our business partners in terms of service level and regulatory compliance. Since our establishment, we have been running an exchange cooperation business model for liquidity sharing with Bitstamp.</blockquote><blockquote>“As Bitstamp is a regulated institution and has extensive experience in crypto markets, we are pleased to partner with it to provide liquidity for our clients. Through this collaboration, our crypto customers have the chance to experience digital asset services at the banking quality level.”</blockquote><p><strong>Jean-Baptiste Graftieaux, Global CEO of Bitstamp, said: </strong></p><blockquote>“As the industry continues to make headway towards mainstream adoption through improvements to transparency, security and customer protection, this partnership is an exciting next step in making crypto more accessible, for everyone. We are privileged to have been chosen as the first crypto exchange to partner with one of Turkey’s top-tier private banks, Garanti BBVA, and look forward to working closely with them to drive forward mainstream adoption for digital asset adoption.”</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Holiday notice: Payment processing pauses during holidays in Dec 2024 and Jan 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/holiday-notice-payment-processing-pauses-during-holidays-in-dec-2024-and-jan-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/holiday-notice-payment-processing-pauses-during-holidays-in-dec-2024-and-jan-2025/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bitstamp incoming and outgoing USD, EUR, and GBP payments will be paused during the holidays in December 2024 and January 2025 in the US, EU, and UK. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="usd-payments"><strong>USD payments</strong></h2><p>Due to the upcoming public holidays, Bitstamp’s bank payment clearing system for incoming and outgoing USD payments won’t be available on December 25, 2024, and January 1, 2025. Deposits and withdrawals will be processed the next business day.</p><h2 id="eur-and-gbp-payments">EUR and GBP payments</h2><p>Similarly, for EUR and GBP payments, the system will be paused on December 25 and 26, 2024, and January 1, 2025, except for Faster Payments and SEPA Instant payments, which will remain available. Deposits and withdrawals will be processed the next business day.</p><p>For all currencies Credit card, Google Pay, Apple Pay, and PayPal transfers will remain unaffected.</p><p>For any assistance or further information, please reach out to us at <a href="mailto:support@bitstamp.net" rel="noreferrer noopener">support@bitstamp.net</a>.</p><p>Wishing all our customers a joyful holiday season!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitstamp Earn Lending: November 2024 Performance Report is here]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-earn-lending-november-2024-performance-report-is-here/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-earn-lending-november-2024-performance-report-is-here/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[November was big for crypto. See how it shaped Bitstamp Earn Lending. Our latest report is packed with insights and key highlights.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>November was a blockbuster month in the world of crypto! With sentiment soaring and records being shattered, it was hard to miss the energy pulsing through the market. Now, we’re taking a closer look at how this energy shaped Bitstamp’s Earn Lending product.</p><p>Our <strong>November 2024 Lending Performance Report</strong> is live, and it’s packed with insights for you. Together with our lending partner Tesseract, we’ve put together a report that dives into the numbers, highlights key market trends, and showcases the performance of our lending portfolios.</p><h2 id="what-s-inside-the-report">What’s inside the report?</h2><p>Whether you’re a seasoned lender or just curious about how it all works, this report has something for everyone. You’ll find:</p><ul><li><strong>Market highlights</strong>: A snapshot of the lending landscape during a booming month for crypto.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Portfolio performance</strong>: A transparent view of how Bitstamp Earn Lending delivered in November.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Risk overview</strong>: Understand the product’s outcomes and associated risks in straightforward, no-jargon terms.</li></ul><p>We know that trust and clarity are everything when it comes to lending. That’s why this report gives you the full picture, broken down in a way that’s easy to follow.</p><p><a href="https://assets.bitstamp.net/msc/Lending_report_A4_nov_a332cce7f2.pdf">Download the lending report now</a></p><hr><p><em>* The availability of Bitstamp Earn Lending depends on many considerations, including the entity to which you are onboarded and the jurisdiction where you reside. Lending is not available in the US, UK, and Singapore.</em></p><p><em>We take every measure possible to protect your assets; however, <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/faq/lending-risk-disclosure/" rel="noopener noreferrer">you should get to know the possible risks</a>.</em></p><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>risks</em></a><em>. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High-volume traders! FastPass to Bitstamp’s standout welcome fees!]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/high-volume-traders-fastpass-to-bitstamps-standout-welcome-fees/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/high-volume-traders-fastpass-to-bitstamps-standout-welcome-fees/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Traders managing over $500k in monthly volume on other platforms can qualify for our exclusive up to 6-month pricing offer. Apply for Bitstamp FastPass today!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For traders handling high volumes, every bit of saved capital adds up fast. We get it! You’re in crypto to make the most out of every trade, not to watch fees eat into your balance. That’s why Bitstamp is known for its highly competitive fee structure.</p><p>When you see fees that are too high for your liking or hidden costs buried in the fine print of other platforms, now you can simply say, “Nah, I’ll FastPass!”<strong> </strong>and rather decide on standout welcome fees with FastPass!</p><h2 id="introducing-bitstamp-fastpass">Introducing Bitstamp FastPass</h2><p>Bitstamp FastPass is a welcome program designed to give you, high-volume traders handling over $500,000 in monthly volume, the benefit of significantly reduced trading fees for up to six months.</p><p><strong>Does your monthly trading volume on all other platforms exceed $5M?</strong> You can unlock ultra-low fees of 0.01% (1bp) for both maker and taker trades.</p><p><strong>Does your monthly trading volume on all other platforms fall between $500K and $5M?</strong> You’ll be able to enjoy highly competitive fees of 0.03% (3bp) for maker and taker trades.</p><p>It’s a straightforward way to experience Bitstamp’s competitive rates right from the start, <strong>with no hidden costs or complicated terms to slow you down. </strong>Keep in mind that the reduced trading fees are only available on Pro modes of Bitstamp's web platform and app, so make sure to trade on Pro to get these rates.</p><h2 id="how-to-get-started-with-bitstamp-fastpass">How to get started with Bitstamp FastPass?</h2><p>With FastPass, you’re in control! No barriers, just lower fees. Here’s how the program works:</p><ul><li><strong>Check if you qualify: </strong>To be eligible, you need to have achieved a monthly trading volume of $500,000 or more on other crypto spot exchanges for at least one month within the last three months.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Apply by sending proof</strong>: Send an email to <a href="mailto:fast.pass@bitstamp.net">fast.pass@bitstamp.net</a> with proof of your trading volume. Screenshots of trading history from one or a mix of exchanges are sufficient as documentation.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Enjoy your welcome fee offer:</strong> If you’ve traded $5M+ monthly, you’ll enjoy 0.01% maker/taker fees. And if you’ve traded between $500K and &lt;$5M monthly, you’ll get 0.03% maker/taker fees.</li></ul><ul><li><strong>Start saving with 3+3 months of exceptional fees</strong>: Once approved, you'll receive a 3-month pricing deal that starts at the beginning of the next month. Hit at least 50% of your customized trading target during this period to extend your reduced fees for an additional 3 months.</li></ul><h3 id="save-long-term-with-bitstamp">Save long-term with Bitstamp</h3><p>After the FastPass period, Bitstamp’s regular rates remain competitive, so you know you’re trading on a platform designed to keep costs low even beyond the initial offer. FastPass is your gateway to exceptionally low fees upfront, but we continue to deliver value for high-volume traders over the long term. Additionally, VIP rates are available for qualifying traders. To learn more, contact our team at fast.pass@bitstamp.net.</p><h3 id="say-i-ll-fastpass-and-save-on-fees-with-confidence">Say “I’ll FastPass” and save on fees with confidence</h3><p>So, if you’re ready for a smarter trading experience that respects your success, just say, “I’ll FastPass with Bitstamp” and enjoy the difference.</p><p>Apply now today: <a href="mailto:fast.pass@bitstamp.net" rel="noreferrer noopener">fast.pass@bitstamp.net</a></p><hr><p><em>Don't invest unless you're prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and you should not expect to be protected if something goes wrong. FastPass is not available in the UK and the states of New York, Nevada and Hawaii.</em></p><p><em>Bitstamp USA, Inc. is licensed to engage in Virtual Currency Business Activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitstamp Monthly Briefing – November 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-monthly-briefing-november-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-monthly-briefing-november-2024/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Bullish sentiment, standout assets, and the forces shaping crypto. Everything you need to know about November and what’s coming next.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>November was a turning point for the crypto market, with bullish sentiment sparking strong momentum across the board. Total market cap surged, key assets like Stellar and Ripple outperformed expectations, and market dynamics continued to evolve in response to global forces.</p><p>In such a fast-moving market, having the right insights can make all the difference; because strategy starts with staying informed. That’s why we’re bringing you November’s monthly briefing, covering market trends, key performers, and the forces shaping crypto’s future.</p><p>Ready?</p><h2 id="market-update">Market update</h2><p>The total crypto market cap increased by 44.6% month-over-month, reaching $3.33 trillion at the end of November. Trading volume on the leading crypto spot exchanges we monitor saw a 137% increase during this period.</p><p>BTC's market dominance decreased by 3.03 percentage points month-over-month to 57.2%.</p><p><strong>Total crypto market cap </strong>(grey)<strong> and BTC dominance </strong>(green)</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.bitstamp.net/bts-img/2024/12/btc-dominance-nov.png" class="kg-image" alt></figure><p><em>Source: </em><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/TOTAL/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em><strong>Total crypto market cap</strong></em></a><em><strong>,</strong> </em><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTC.D/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em><strong>Bitcoin dominance</strong></em></a></p><p><em>Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of crypto assets can be highly volatile. Data taken on December 1, 2024. </em></p><h3 id="best-performing-cmc-100-assets-in-november">Best performing CMC 100 assets in November</h3><ul><li><strong>+468.1% Stellar (XLM) – </strong>Stellar’s <a href="https://www.fxstreet.com/cryptocurrencies/news/stellar-price-forecast-eyes-for-further-gains-as-bounces-off-support-level-and-bullish-on-chain-metrics-202411291532" rel="noreferrer noopener">total value locked (TVL) more than doubled</a> in November, indicating the network’s expanding use case and growing bullish sentiment.</li><li><strong>+287.9% Algorand (ALGO) – </strong>The rally was driven by <a href="https://www.fxstreet.com/cryptocurrencies/news/algorand-reaches-fresh-two-year-high-supported-by-bullish-on-chain-metrics-202411291306" rel="noreferrer noopener">bullish on-chain metrics</a> and expectations of a favorable regulatory shift.</li><li><strong>+282.9% Ripple (XRP) – </strong>The rally was fueled by optimism surrounding a <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/xrp-price-surge-trump-win-sec-legal-battle" rel="noreferrer noopener">favorable outcome in the SEC lawsuit</a>, a more supportive regulatory environment, and excitement over a potential stablecoin project.</li></ul><h3 id="worst-performing-cmc-100-assets-in-november">Worst performing CMC 100 assets in November</h3><ul><li><strong>-14.3% Popcat (SOL) (POPCAT) – </strong>The strong uptrend reversed shortly after <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/popcat-sol/" rel="noreferrer noopener">reaching a new ATH</a> in the middle of the month.</li></ul><p><em>Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of crypto assets can be highly volatile. Data taken on December 1, 2024. </em></p><h3 id="key-macro-crypto-events-in-december-2024">Key macro &amp; crypto events in December 2024</h3><ul><li><strong>December 9-10</strong>: <a href="https://b.tc/conference/mena" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin MENA</a> in Abu Dhabi, UAE</li><li><strong>December 9-11</strong>: <a href="https://afrobitcoin.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Africa Bitcoin Conference</a> in Nairobi, Kenya</li><li><strong>December 10-14</strong>: <a href="https://www.taipeiblockchainweek.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Taipei Blockchain Week</a> in Taipei, Taiwan</li><li><strong>December 11</strong>: US Inflation &amp; Core Inflation rate</li><li><strong>December 12</strong>: Governing Council of the ECB in Frankfurt, Germany</li><li><strong>December 12-13</strong>: <a href="https://www.globalblockchainshow.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Global Blockchain Show</a> in Dubai, UAE</li><li><strong>December 16-18</strong>: <a href="https://theblockchainassociation.org/policy-summit-2024/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Policy Summit</a> in Washington, D.C.</li><li><strong>December 18</strong>: Fed Interest rate decision &amp; press conference</li><li><strong>December 18</strong>: FOMC Economic projections</li></ul><h2 id="unpacking-the-forces-shaping-crypto">Unpacking the forces shaping crypto</h2><p>The year 2024 held several potential determinative factors for the future of the cryptocurrency market, particularly the approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs in the U.S. and the implementation of the Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) framework in Europe. Looking ahead, the future of crypto appears poised for dynamic developments shaped by regulatory frameworks, economic factors, and U.S. political initiatives under Trump’s reelection.</p><h3 id="regulation-and-policy-shifts">Regulation and policy shifts</h3><p>The European Union has set a benchmark for comprehensive crypto regulation with its Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) framework, implemented in 2024. MiCA provides a unified legal framework across EU member states, focusing on licensing, consumer protection, and financial stability. This approach is expected to enhance Europe’s appeal as a hub for crypto innovation by reducing regulatory uncertainty for businesses and investors.</p><p>The U.S. has also seen significant regulatory activity, including the SEC’s approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs, marking a pivotal moment for institutional crypto adoption. Key legislative efforts include stablecoin oversight (e.g., the Clarity for Payment Stablecoins Act) and redefining regulatory frameworks through the Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act. These laws aim to shift oversight of many crypto assets from the SEC to the CFTC, clarifying the legal status of digital assets as either securities or commodities, aligning with global efforts such as Europe’s MiCA framework.</p><p>Under the Biden administration, the U.S. has taken a cautious regulatory approach to crypto, emphasizing investor protection and financial stability. However, this approach often translates into ambiguous or restrictive policies, pushing some crypto innovation overseas. Donald Trump’s return to the presidency could signal a shift in U.S. crypto policy. His campaign promises to replace SEC Chair Gary Gensler with a crypto-friendly figure, halt the development of a U.S. CBDC, establish a Bitcoin strategic reserve, and form a crypto advisory council may foster institutional adoption and encourage transparent regulations.</p><h3 id="macroeconomic-factors-and-institutional-adoption">Macroeconomic factors and institutional adoption</h3><p>Globally, the trajectory of inflation, interest rates, and economic recovery will significantly impact the crypto market. During periods of high inflation, cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin are often promoted as hedges against fiat currency devaluation. However, rising interest rates can weaken crypto’s appeal as a speculative asset, as investors turn to safer, yield-generating options. The Federal Reserve’s monetary policy will remain a critical determinant of market sentiment.</p><p>Institutional interest in blockchain technology and cryptocurrencies is expected to grow, driven by advancements in DeFi, the tokenization of real-world assets, and developments in Layer-2 scaling solutions. Major corporations are also increasingly integrating blockchain solutions for supply chain management, payments, and data security.</p><h3 id="outlook">Outlook</h3><p>The next four years are likely to see a dual narrative in cryptocurrency markets. Regions like the EU may solidify their leadership through balanced regulations, while the U.S. could face a critical juncture depending on its political direction. If Trump’s promises materialize, the U.S. could reclaim its position as a leader in blockchain innovation. However, macroeconomic pressures, global regulatory competition, and technological breakthroughs will collectively determine the future trajectory of the crypto sector. This period could either catalyze crypto’s integration into mainstream finance or highlight its speculative vulnerabilities, depending on the execution of policies and global economic conditions.</p><h2 id="recommended-reads">Recommended reads</h2><p><strong>Bitcoin L2s by </strong><a href="https://www.galaxy.com/insights/research/bitcoin-layer-2-modular-future/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Gabe Parker, Galaxy research</strong></a></p><p>Bitcoin Layer 2 (L2) solutions are rapidly evolving to address Bitcoin's scalability and usability limitations, growing from 10 to 75 projects since 2021. These L2s, including rollups and sidechains, leverage independent execution environments to bypass Bitcoin's base-layer constraints, enabling DeFi, tokenization, and yield-generating applications. With $447 million in venture funding since 2018—36% of it in 2024—L2s aim to attract liquidity from native Bitcoin holders and wrapped BTC users on Ethereum. By 2030, it’s estimated that $47 billion worth of BTC (2.3% of total supply) could be bridged to these ecosystems if issues like competitive yields, robust ecosystems, and trust in bridge mechanisms are addressed.</p><p><strong>A Data-Driven Update on Stablecoins by </strong><a href="https://coinmetrics.substack.com/p/state-of-the-network-issue-286" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Coin Metrics</strong></a></p><p>The stablecoin market has expanded significantly, with a total supply reaching $189 billion, led by Tether’s USDT at 66% market share and Ethereum hosting 55% of all stablecoin issuance. Stablecoins are vital for liquidity in both bull and bear markets, facilitating trading and on-chain transactions. Stablecoins trading volume recently surged to $120 billion. Platforms like Solana and Ethereum are seeing record high stablecoin usage, driven by low fees and high adoption. Meanwhile, innovative yield-driven models like Ethena’s USDe are growing rapidly, leveraging funding rates and staking mechanisms. Regulatory clarity is expected to further bolster stablecoin adoption and evolution.</p><p><strong>MicroStrategy’s End Game by </strong><a href="https://thewolfden.substack.com/p/the-wolf-den-1062-microstrategys" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>The Woolf Den</strong></a></p><p>The Wolf Den analyzes MicroStrategy's remarkable performance, including a 568% annual stock gain, driven by Michael Saylor's aggressive BTC acquisition strategy. Saylor envisions transforming the company into a leading “Bitcoin bank,” leveraging low-interest debt and innovative financial instruments to accumulate Bitcoin at scale. With holdings exceeding 252,000 BTC (around 1.5% of the adjusted total supply), Saylor predicts Bitcoin's value reaching millions per coin, potentially fueling a trillion-dollar valuation for MicroStrategy. While the strategy excites many, it raises concerns about speculative risks, regulatory intervention, and overvaluation, as the stock trades at a premium to its Bitcoin assets.</p><p><strong>Short-Term vs. Long-Term Forecasts by </strong><a href="https://mailchi.mp/verdadcap/short-term-vs-long-term-forecasts?e=513c9c4eac" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Luke Burke &amp; Daniel Rasmussen</strong></a></p><p>This blog examines the challenges of economic forecasting, highlighting how accuracy declines over longer time horizons. A study by the Federal Reserve Bank of New York found that short-term forecasts (within a year) are more reliable, with forecasters often underestimating their accuracy, while long-term forecasts are prone to overconfidence and significant errors. Equity analysts also show similar patterns, with short-term cash flow predictions aligning reasonably well with outcomes, except during recessions. Longer-term forecasts often reflect irrational optimism or pessimism, making them unreliable and sometimes contrarian indicators of future market performance.</p><hr><p><em>No information in this blog is intended to provide any personal investment services or advice nor is it an investment recommendation. Clients are responsible for making their own investment decisions. Bitstamp accepts no responsibility for any damage and/or loss arising from the use of information provided herein. Past performance is not necessarily an indicator of future results. Please consider your individual position and financial goals before making an independent investment decision. </em></p><p><em>Bitstamp is licensed to engage in virtual currency business activity by the New York State Department of Financial Services. Licensed as a Money Transmitter by the New York State Department of Financial Services.</em></p><p><em>Not offered in the following states: Hawaii and Nevada</em></p><p><em>Bitstamp UK Limited is registered with the UK's Financial Conduct Authority. Please read the </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Risk Warning Statement</em></a><em> before investing. Cryptoassets and cryptoasset services are not regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. You are unlikely to be protected if something goes wrong. Your investment may go down as well as up. You may be liable to pay Capital Gains Tax on any profits you earn.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway Terms]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/cryptowarmup-holiday-giveaway-terms/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/cryptowarmup-holiday-giveaway-terms/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[By participating in the #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway (“Giveaway”) you agree to accept and comply with these terms (“Terms”).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Acceptance of the Terms</strong></p><p>By participating in the #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway (“<strong>Giveaway</strong>”) you agree to accept and comply with these terms (“<strong>Terms</strong>”).</p><p><strong>CONSUMER NOTICE</strong>: You have not yet earned a reward. No purchase or payment is necessary to enter this Giveaway. You should read the entire Terms carefully before participating in the Giveaway.</p><p>As used in these Terms, “<strong>Bitstamp</strong>” refers to Bitstamp Limited, a company incorporated under the laws of England and Wales, registered with the Registrar of Companies for England and Wales under the registration number 08157033, with its registered address at 5 New Street Square, EC4A 3TW London, United Kingdom and its affiliated companies.</p><p><strong>Giveaway period</strong></p><p>Giveaway will be active from 9 December 2024 at 12:15 CET until 13 December 2024 at 23:59 (“<strong>Giveaway Period</strong>”).</p><p><strong>Who can participate? </strong></p><p>Each natural person with X account who is above 18 years old can participate in the Giveaway, excluding residents of Afghanistan, Argentina, Brazil, China, Columbia, Congo (Brazzaville), Congo (Kinshasa), Cuba, Hawaii, India, Iran, Israel, Libya, Nepal, Nevada, North Korea, Peru, Russia, Serbia, Spain, Somalia, Syria, Taiwan, the United Kingdom, Turkey, Ukraine (the “<strong>Participant</strong>”).</p><p>Bitstamp’s employees and their immediate families, associated agents, and anyone personally connected with Giveaway are not eligible to participate.</p><p><strong>How to participate?</strong></p><p>Giveaway will be held exclusively on X. To enter the Giveaway, the Participant is required to fulfil the following conditions cumulatively:</p><ul><li>follow @Bitstamp on X;</li><li>like and repost the original #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway post, posted on the Bitstamp X account;</li><li>leave a comment under #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway post, tag one person, and answer the question: Which crypto coin is keeping you warm?</li></ul><p><strong>PARTICIPATION RESTRICTION</strong>: Each Participant may only participate once. Any Participant using multiple X accounts or multiple Mail In Entries to participate in the Giveaway will be suspended. Non-compliance with any of these stipulated conditions will result in disqualification from the Giveaway.</p><p><strong>Alternative method to participate for US customers only:</strong> Participants in the US may mail a postcard, including Participant’s complete name, mailing address (no P.O. Boxes), daytime phone number, email address, and birth date to: <em>BITSTAMP USA, INC., Attn: #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway, 27 Union Square West, Suite 205, New York, NY 10003</em>. Each postcard must be mailed and must be postmarked during the period starting 9 December 2024 at 12:15 CET and for entry into the Giveaway, all postcards must be received by 13 December 2024 at 23:59 CET (the “<strong>Mail In Entry</strong>”). Photocopied, illegible or mechanically produced entries are not eligible. All entries become the property of Bitstamp, and will not be returned, and no receipt of confirmation will be provided. Bitstamp is not responsible for lost, late, damaged, misdirected or postage-due mailed entries.</p><p><strong>Prize</strong></p><p>The winners of the Giveaway will receive a Bitstamp sweater (the “<strong>Prize</strong>”).</p><p><strong>PRIZE RESTRICTIONS</strong>: Limit of one (1) Prize per Participant based on X account.</p><p>Total Prize value is 1.082,68 EUR (1139.25 USD). The Prize value per Participant is 51,56 EUR (54.25 USD).</p><p><strong>Selection of the Winners</strong></p><p>21 (twenty-one) Participants will be selected to receive a Prize from the pool of submissions (the ‘’<strong>Winners</strong>’’), within 12 hours after the Giveaway period ends. Selection of the Winners will be determined at Bitstamp’s discretion, based on evaluation of the comment under the #CryptoWarmUp Holiday Giveaway post submitted during the Giveaway period.</p><p>After the selection of the Winners, the Winners will be vetted against the eligibility criteria of these Terms. Non-eligible Winners will be disqualified, and another Winner will be selected in line with these Terms. If anyhow, no Winner satisfies the eligibility criteria, Bitstamp reserves the right to not distribute the Prize.</p><p><strong>Notification to the Winners</strong></p><p>Bitstamp will reach out to Winners by sending a direct message to the Winners on X, on 14 December 2024. Additionally, the Winners will be tagged in a post on Bitstamp X account announcing the Winners after the Giveaway Period ends. Bitstamp will provide the Winners with a link to Microsoft Form, where Winners will be required to complete a form within 48 hours of receiving the message (the ''<strong>Response period</strong>''). After the Response period, Bitstamp will forward the details of all Winners to our partner Ugly Christmas Sweater Inc., who will handle the delivery of the Prizes. All Prizes will be shipped by Ugly Christmas Sweater Inc. within 1 week after the Response period ends.</p><p><strong>Reservations</strong></p><p>Bitstamp may, at its sole discretion, at any time:</p><ul><li>disqualify the Participant and/or not award the Prize if the Participant violates these Giveaway Terms, undermines the operation of the Giveaway, threatens other participants and/or Bitstamp, or performs any other action deemed unfair by Bitstamp;</li><li>modify the Terms and/or cancel the Giveaway without the need to indicate the grounds;</li><li>adopt any other appropriate measures to protect the legitimate operation of this Giveaway and Bitstamp’s interests.</li></ul><p><strong>Limitation of Liability</strong></p><p>To the extent that it is permitted by law, Bitstamp excludes all liability whether arising in tort, contract or otherwise for any personal injury or any other loss or damage, including, without limitation, loss of opportunity or loss of profits, whether direct, indirect, special, or consequential, arising in any way out of the Giveaway, including, without limitation, to:</p><ul><li>any technical difficulties or equipment malfunction (whether or not under Bitstamp’s control);</li><li>any entry that is late, lost, altered, damaged or misdirected due to any reason beyond the reasonable control of Bitstamp;</li></ul><ul><li>any tax implications; or</li><li>the Prize or use of the Prize.</li></ul><p><strong>Tax Reporting </strong></p><p>In case a tax reporting, along withany potential withholding tax payment obligation is imposed on Bitstamp on the basis of applicable local tax procedure provisions, Bitstamp reserves the right to such reporting and remittance of withholding tax to applicable tax authorities. Such reporting may require additional documentation and information from the Winner. Delivery of complete and signed documentation and/or delivery of information required by Bitstamp in accordance with the set deadline is required for the Winner to be eligible for the Prize. Please note that such reporting and any potential income tax withheld and paid by Bitstamp (if required by local tax legislation) will not affect the Prize received. If applicable, Bitstamp will provide you with information on the amount of the Prize received and potential income tax paid.</p><p>Bitstamp is, however, not responsible for any other taxes and fees that may arise in connection with the awarded prizes, to the extent that Bitstamp is not obliged to withhold and pay such taxes and fees in accordance with the applicable legislation.</p><p>Each Winner is furthermore solely responsible for reporting and paying any and all applicable taxes related to the Prize and for any other similar costs associated with the Prize acceptance on their side.</p><p>Bitstamp advises Winners to consult with an accountant or a tax professional to determine the tax implications of accepting and using, including, to the extent applicable, conducting transactions with, the Prize.</p><p><strong>Data Protection</strong></p><p>Participants hereby consent to processing of personal data by Bitstamp and Ugly Christmas Sweater Inc. for the purpose of administrating the Giveaway and to distribute the Prize to Winners.</p><p>All personal data are processed by Bitstamp in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.</p><p>For any further information on how Bitstamp processes personal data, please refer to Bitstamp’s <a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/privacy-policy/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Privacy Policy</a>.</p><p><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><p>If any provision of these Terms become invalid, this shall not affect the validity of the remaining provisions.</p><p>These Terms are governed by the laws of Delaware, without reference to conflict of laws principles. Any dispute, conflict or disagreement arising from or connected to these Terms shall be finally settled by the courts of Delaware.</p><p>The Participant may at any time withdraw from the participation in the Giveaway by sending a notice to <a href="mailto:support@bitstamp.net" rel="noreferrer noopener">support@bitstamp.net</a>.</p><p>Complaints and claims relating to the Giveaway must be addressed exclusively to Bitstamp at <a href="mailto:support@bitstamp.net" rel="noreferrer noopener">support@bitstamp.net</a></p><p><strong>Contact</strong></p><p>For any queries with respect to the Giveaway do not hesitate to contact us at <a href="mailto:support@bitstamp.net" rel="noreferrer noopener">support@bitstamp.net</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New listings: OP, ARB, and SEI are live on Bitstamp!]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/new-listings-op-arb-and-sei-are-live-on-bitstamp/</link>
            <guid>https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/new-listings-op-arb-and-sei-are-live-on-bitstamp/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Discover three new additions to Bitstamp: Optimism (OP), Arbitrum (ARB), and Sei (SEI). Do they fit into your portfolio?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for something new? Another asset to enhance your portfolio? This time, you can pick and choose from three exciting new additions to Bitstamp: Optimism ($OP), Arbitrum ($ARB), and Sei ($SEI).</p><h2 id="start-trading-them-today">Start trading them today</h2><p>We’re listing the following pairs globally.*</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/op/usd/">OP/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/op/eur/">OP/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/sei/usd/">SEI/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/sei/eur/">SEI/EUR</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/arb/usd/">ARB/USD</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/markets/arb/eur/">ARB/EUR</a></p><h2 id="what-is-optimism">What is Optimism?</h2><p>Optimism is a <strong>layer-two solution</strong> built on Ethereum that speeds up transactions and lowers costs, while still benefiting from Ethereum's security. It does this through <strong>optimistic rollups</strong>, meaning transactions are recorded on Optimism’s blockchain but are ultimately secured on Ethereum.</p><p>The OP token is a key player in Optimism’s ecosystem, supporting decentralized finance (DeFi) and decentralized apps (dApps). With over <strong>$500 million in total value locked</strong> and platforms like <strong>Uniswap</strong> and <strong>Synthetix</strong> already using it, Optimism is making a real impact in scaling Ethereum.</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-optimism-op/">Start to learn more about Optimism OP</a></p><h2 id="what-is-sei">What is SEI?</h2><p><strong>SEI </strong>is the native token of the Sei blockchain network, which is the first Layer 1 blockchain that’s specifically tailored for decentralized exchanges. By optimizing for high transaction volumes and low fees, Sei <strong>allows DEXes to compete more effectively</strong> in the fast-moving crypto market. It also supports NFT and in-game item exchanges, making it versatile for a wide range of decentralized finance applications.</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-sei/">Start to learn more about SEI</a></p><h2 id="what-is-arbitrum"><strong><strong><strong>What is Arbitrum?</strong></strong></strong></h2><p>Arbitrum is a layer-two solution built on top of Ethereum. It helps make Ethereum transactions faster, cheaper, and more efficient by moving most of the work off-chain. This means you can enjoy lower fees and quicker transactions, without losing the security that Ethereum provides. Arbitrum’s technology is already being used by some of the biggest DeFi platforms.</p><p>The <strong>ARB</strong> token is used for governance, which means holders get to vote on important decisions, upgrades, and how the network moves forward through the <strong>Arbitrum DAO</strong> (Decentralized Autonomous Organization).</p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/learn/cryptocurrency-guide/what-is-arbitrum/">Start to learn more about Arbitrum ARB</a></p><p><strong><strong><strong>Curious?</strong></strong></strong></p><p><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/onboarding/login/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Log in</a> to your Bitstamp account to start trading and get the Bitstamp mobile app (available on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bitstamp-buy-btc-and-more/id1406825640" rel="noreferrer noopener">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.bitstamp.app&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>) to manage all our cryptocurrencies on the go!</p><hr><p><em>*The listing schedule times might be subject to change. The pairs are listed globally, except in Singapore and the United States. </em></p><p><em>Don’t invest unless you’re prepared to lose all the money you invest. This is a high-risk investment and may not be suitable for all investors. Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. The performance of cryptoassets can be highly volatile. Learn more about </em><a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/legal/risk-warning/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>risks</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>